
{
  
"Quiz" :  [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "What was Gandalf also known as?",
    "answer": "Mithrandir",
    "options": [
      "Incánus",
      "Mithrandir",
      "Curumo",
      "Tharkûn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "Which birthday does Bilbo celebrate at the beginning of The Fellowship of the Ring?",
    "answer": "His 111",
    "options": [
      "His 100",
      "His 101",
      "His 111",
      "His 110"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "How many wizards are there in Middle Earth?",
    "answer": "Five",
    "options": [
      "Three",
      "Four",
      "Six",
      "Five"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "Who does Sam marry at the end of The Return of the King?",
    "answer": "Mount Doom",
    "options": [
      "Pearly Bottom",
      "Rossie Cotton",
      "Daisy Puddle",
      "Jilly Took"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "What is the name of the local pub in Hobbiton?",
    "answer": "The Green Dragon",
    "options": [
      "The Black Boar",
      "The Prancing Poney",
      "The Burgundy Lion",
      "The Green Dragon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "category":"easy",
    "question": "What is Legolas's last name?",
    "answer": "Greenleaf",
    "options": [
      "Evenstar",
      "Greenleaf",
      "Lightfoot",
      "Celeborn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "category":"easy",
    "question": "How many rings were given to the elves?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": [
      "9",
      "3",
      "4",
      "1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "How many great rings were made in total?",
    "answer": "20",
    "options": [
      "7",
      "13",
      "20",
      "17"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "After King Theoden’s death at the Battle of Helm’s Deep, who takes over as the new ruler of Rohan?",
    "answer": "Eowyn",
    "options": [
      "Helm HammerHand",
      "Eomer",
      "Eowyn",
      "Grimbold"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "By what name were the Balrog also known?",
    "answer": "Durin's Bane",
    "options": [
      "Flaming whips",
      "Durin's Bane",
      "Shadow monsters",
      "Shadows of Zirakzigil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "Where does Frodo go at the end of the books?",
    "answer": "The Undying Lands",
    "options": [
      "The Unifying Lands",
      "The Plains of Tomorrow",
      "The Mysterious Plains",
      "The Undying Lands"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "category": "easy",
    "question": "What´s the elvish word for friend?",
    "answer": "Mellon",
    "options": [
      "Timpatur",
      "Papallon",
      "Mangonn",
      "Mellon"
      ]
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "What does Arwen mean in Elfish?",
    "answer": "Noble Maiden",
    "options": [
      "Star",
      "Morning Flower",
      "Noble Maiden",
      "Green Woods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "Where does the Fellowship of the Ring break up?",
    "answer": "Amon Hen",
    "options": [
      "Lothlorein",
      "Osgiliath",
      "Amon Hen",
      "Moria"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "category":"medium",
    "question": "The three Stone-Trolls of the Lone-lands were called what?",
    "answer": "Tom, Bert, and William",
    "options": [
      "Oin, Gloin and Foin",
      "Bach, Walt and Edward",
      "Tony, Don and Peter",
      "Tom, Bert, and William"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "category":"medium",
    "question": "In Mordor, what kind of food does Frodo say he can't remember the taste of?",
    "answer": "Strawberries",
    "options": [
      "Cheese",
      "Strawberries",
      "Mushrooms",
      "Bacon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "How´s it called Aragorn's and sam´s horses?(in order)",
    "answer": "Bill, brego",
    "options": [
      "Frada, shadowfax",
      "Hasufel, Arod",
      "Bill, brego",
      "Asfaloth, Snowmane"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "What is Wormtongue’s real name?",
    "answer": "Grima",
    "options": [
      "Lotho",
      "Larma",
      "Grima",
      "Dourif"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "What does R.R stand for in author J.R.R Tolkien's name?",
    "answer": "Ronald Reuel",
    "options": [
      "Ryan Rhoades",
      "Richard Ryland",
      "Robert Remingron",
      "Ronald Reuel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "Which healing herb did Aragorn use to slow down the poison after Frodo was stabbed with a Morgul blade?",
    "answer": "Athelas",
    "options": [
      "Olvar",
      "Niphredil",
      "Pipe-weed",
      "Athelas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "In 'Lord of the Rings', what was the name of Gandalf's sword?",
    "answer": "Glamdring",
    "options": [
      "Wandlax",
      "Eomer",
      "Glamdring",
      "Excalamir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "what is the Elvish word for Ent?",
    "answer": "Onod",
    "options": [
      "Onod",
      "Inid",
      "Anad",
      "Ithil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": " Which member of the thirteen Dwarves in 'The Hobbit' does Frodo meet in Rivendell?",
    "answer": "Gloin",
    "options": [
      "Gloin",
      "Thorin",
      "Balin",
      "Bofur"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "Who was the first king of Numenor?",
    "answer": "Elros",
    "options": [
      "Elros",
      "Isildur",
      "Elendil",
      "Glorfindel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "category": "medium",
    "question": "When Aragorn was taken to Rivendell when he was a baby so to be hidden from Sauron as an heir to Isildur, what was the name he was given?",
    "answer": "Estel",
    "options": [
      "Elendil",
      "Aldarion",
      "Minyatur",
      "Estel"
    ]
  }
  
  ]
}
